Guide to the Charles S. Ascher Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Charles S. Ascher Papers,
1926-1979.
Ascher, Charles S. (Charles Stern), 1899-1980.
68 linear ft (ca. 95,000 items in 159 boxes & 11 rolls).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078775
History
Professor of political science at Brooklyn College from 1949 to his retirement in 1966. (Columbia A.B., 1920; LL.B., 1921). He was also secretary and general counsel of the City Housing Corporation, builder of the experimental developments Sunnyside (Queens, N.Y.) and Radburn (New Jersey); served as founding executive secretary of the Public Administration Clearing House in Chicago; regional director of the National Housing Agency from 1942-1947; and executive officer for programs at UNESCO.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, memoranda, manuscripts, documents, photographs, printed material, and memorabilia of Ascher. Also, his notes and diary/datebooks, as well as typescripts for many of his reports, articles, and reviews. Among the major correspondents are Roger Nash Baldwin, Mary Steichen Calderone, Julian Huxley, Margaret Mead, Jo Mielziner, Lewis Mumford, Alva Myrdal, Edwin Herbert Samuel (2nd Viscount Samuel), Percy E. Sutton, and Constantine D. Tsatsos.
Subjects
Brooklyn College.--Faculty.; City Housing Corporation.; Public Administration Clearing House.; United States.--National Housing Agency.; American Society of Public Administration.; Citizens Housing and Planning Council (New York, N.Y.); International Institute of Administrative Sciences.; International Union of Local Authorities.; Unesco.; Baldwin, Roger N. (Roger Nash), 1884-1981.; Calderone, Mary Steichen, 1904-1998.; Huxley, Julian, 1887-1975.; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978.; Mielziner, Jo, 1901-1976.; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990.; Myrdal, Alva, 1902-1986.; Samuel, Edward Herbert.; Sutton, Percy E.; Tsatsos, Kōnstantinos, 1899-1987.; Sunnyside (New York, N.Y.); Radburn (N.J.); Political science.; City planning--New York (State)--New York.; City planning--New Jersey.; Housing--New York (State)--New York.; Housing development--New York (State)--New York.; Diaries.; Photoprints.; College teachers.
Acquisition
1980 M80 Estate of Charles S. Ascher Gift
Gift of the estate of Charles S. Ascher, 1980.
Boxes 3-163 are located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
- Series I: Catalogued correspondence
  - Baldwin, Roger Nash (Box 1-2)
  - Bing, Rudolf (Box 1-2)
  - Brooks, Gladys (Mrs. Van Wyck) (Box 1-2)
  - Bunche, Ralph J. (Box 1-2)
  - Calderone, Mary Steichen (Box 1-2)
  - Celler, Emanuel (Box 1-2)
  - Chase, Stuart (Box 1-2)
  - Delano, Frederic A. (Box 1-2)
  - Deutsch, Babette (Box 1-2)
  - Douglas, Paul H. (Box 1-2)
  - Frank, Jerome New (Box 1-2)
  - Freud, Anna (Box 1-2)
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster (Box 1-2)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth (Box 1-2)
  - Gardner, John W. (Box 1-2)
  - Greene, Jerome D. (Box 1-2)
  - Gropius, Walter (Box 1-2)
  - Heckscher, August (Box 1-2)
  - Huebsch, Ben (Box 1-2)
  - Huxley, Julian (Box 1-2)
  - Isaacs, Stanley M. (Box 1-2)
  - Lamont, Corliss (Box 1-2)
  - Lerner, Max (Box 1-2)
  - Lindsay, John Vliet (Box 1-2)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot (Box 1-2)
  - Jackson, Barbara Ward (Lady) (Box 1-2)
  - Javits, Jacob K. (Box 1-2)
  - Jessup, Philip C. (Box 1-2)
  - Johnson, Alvin (Box 1-2)
  - Keating, Kenneth B. (Box 1-2)
  - Kenyon, Dorothy (Box 1-2)
  - Keppel, Frederick P. (Box 1-2)
  - Knopf, Alfred A. (Box 1-2)
  - Maclnnes, Helen (Box 1-2)
  - McCormick, Anne O'Hare (Box 1-2)
  - Mead, Margaret (Box 1-2)
  - Medina, Harold R. (Box 1-2)
  - Meiklejohn, Alexander (Box 1-2)
  - Merriam, Charles E. (Box 1-2)
  - Mielziner, Jo (Box 1-2)
  - Moses, Robert (Box 1-2)
  - Mumford, Lewis (Box 1-2)
  - Myrdal, Alva (Box 1-2)
  - Myrdal, Gunnar (Box 1-2)
  - Nevins, Allan (Box 1-2)
  - Reinhardt, Ad (Box 1-2)
  - Riesman, David (Box 1-2)
  - Rogers, Lindsay (Box 1-2)
  - Samuel, 2nd Viscount (Box 1-2)
  - Samuel, Edwin Herbert (Box 1-2)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr. (Box 1-2)
  - Seligman, Eustace (Box 1-2)
  - Sparkman, John (Box 1-2)
  - Stone, Harlan F. (Box 1-2)
  - Strand, Paul (Box 1-2)
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays (Box 1-2)
  - Sutton, Percy E. (Box 1-2)
  - Thant, U (Box 1-2)
  - Tsatsos, Constantine D. (Box 1-2)
  - Wagner, Robert F., Jr. (Box 1-2)
  - Waldheim, Kurt (Box 1-2)
- Series II: Catalogued manuscripts
  - Ascher, Charles Stern (Box 1-2)
  - Huxley, Julian (Box 1-2)
  - Samuel, Edwin Herbert Samuel, 2nd Viscount (Box 1-2)
  - General Correspondence and Subject File (Box 1-2)
  - A (general) (Box 3)
  - Acheson Statement (Box 4)
  - Adirondack Mountain Club (Box 4)
  - Anthropos (Vassiliou) (Box 4)
  - Annals (Box 4)
  - Ascher, Charles S.:
    - Congratulatory telegrams to (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, Outgoing, 1931-1932 (Box 4)
    - Charles S.- Correspondence, Outgoing miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Financial accounts (Box 4)
  - Ascher, Helen - estate (Box 4)
  - Ascher, Joan - wedding (Box 4)
  - Ascher Family - New York (Box 4)
  - B (general) (Box 4)
  - B (general) (Box 5)
  - B (general) (Box 6)
  - Brickner, R., M.D. (Box 6)
  - Brownlow, Louis (Box 6)
  - Brownlow Festschrift (Box 6)
  - Brownlow Fund (Box 6)
  - C (general) (Box 6)
  - C (general) (Box 7)
  - Canada (general) (Box 8)
  - Canaux, J. (Box 8)
  - Cancer Fund (Box 8)
  - Caro, Robert – The Power Broker (Robert Moses) (Box 8)
  - City University of New York - Bunche Institute (Box 8)
  - City University of New York - Professional Staff and Pension (Box 8)
  - Columbia University (general) (Box 8)
  - Columbia University - Oral History - correspondence (Box 9)
  - D (general) (Box 9)
  - E (general) (Box 9)
  - E (general) (Box 10)
  - Emmerich, H. and J., (2 Folders) (Box 10)
  - Ethical Culture Society (Box 10)
  - F (general) (Box 10)
  - F (general) (Box 11)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 11)
  - Fourmen Management Corporation (Box 11)
  - Fulbright Fellowships (Box 11)
  - G (general) (Box 11)
  - G (general) (Box 12)
  - Gaus, John (Box 12)
  - Government Printing Office, U.S. (Box 12)
  - H (general) (Box 13)
  - Haan (Box 14)
  - Harvard University (Box 14)
  - Hodson Fund (Box 14)
  - Housing and Urban Development, U.S. Department (HUD) (Box 14)
  - I (general) (Box 14)
  - Illinois Bar (Box 14)
  - Informatics (Box 14)
  - Ipsophone (Box 14)
  - Israel (Box 15)
  - J (general) (Box 15)
  - K (general) (Box 15)
  - K (general) (Box 16)
  - Kitimat (Box 16)
  - Kubie (Box 16)
  - L (general) (Box 16)
  - L (general) (Box 17)
  - LaGuardia, Fiorello (material about) (Box 17)
  - Lambda Alpha (Box 18)
  - Land Economics (Box 18)
  - Lasker (Box 18)
  - Lasker Trust (Box 18)
  - Loessner (Box 18)
  - M (general) (Box 19)
  - M (general) (Box 20)
  - Macy Foundation (Box 20)
  - Mumford, Lewis (related material) (Box 20)
  - Muzzey, E.J. (Box 20)
  - N (general) (Box 20)
  - Nassau County (Box 21)
  - National Conference on Urban Planning Education (Box 21)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation (Box 21)
  - New York City (general.) See Also Boxes 67-77, 125-126, 132-133 (Box 21)
  - New York City:
    - Charter Revision (Box 21)
    - 1840 Report (Box 21)
    - Landmarks (Box 21)
    - Mayor and Neighborhood Government (Box 21)
    - Teachers Retirement System (Box 21)
    - Westsider (Box 21)
  - New York State (Box 21)
  - New York State Department of Health (Box 22)
  - New York Times (Box 22)
  - O (general) (Box 22)
  - Olmsted, Frederick Law (related material) (Box 22)
  - "Orchids" (i.e., honors, tributes) (Box 22)
  - Ombudsman (Box 22)
  - P (general) (Box 22)
  - P (general) (Box 23)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 23)
  - Pittsburgh, University of (Box 23)
  - Public Administration Service (Box 23)
  - Public Interest Groups (Box 23)
  - Public Works, International (Box 23)
  - Q (general) (Box 24)
  - R (general) (Box 24)
  - Radburn (Box 25)
  - Regional Science Association (Box 25)
  - Root, Li (Box 25)
  - S (general) (Box 26)
  - S (general) (Box 27)
  - State-County-City Service Center (Box 28)
  - Steinig, Leon (Box 28)
  - Stern Estate (Box 28)
  - Stotzka, H. (Vienna) (Box 28)
  - Sunnyside (Box 28)
  - Syracuse University (Box 28)
  - T (general) (Box 29)
  - Tachau, M. (Box 29)
  - Thoreau, H.D. - Map of Eagleswood (Box 29)
  - U (general) (Box 30)
  - V (general) (Box 30)
  - W (general) (Box 30)
  - W (general) (Box 31)
  - Wood, Elizabeth (Box 31)
  - X-Y-Z (general) (Box 31)
  - Unidentified (Box 31)
- Series III: Manuscripts, Documents and Course Material
  - Ascher, Charles S.: (Box 32)
    - Administration of Publicly Aided Housing, 1971 (Related material) (Box 32)
    - Private Covenants in Urban Redevelopment (Urban Redevelopment Study, 1950)
      - manuscript (Box 32)
      - preliminary draft (mimeograph) (Box 32)
      - correspondence and related material (Box 32)
    - Oral History (Columbia University.) See Also Box 9 (Box 33)
    - Articles Reviews and Speeches (includes reprints) - 1926-1942 (Box 34)
    - Articles Reviews and Speeches (includes reprints) - 1943-1955 (Box 35)
    - Articles Reviews and Speeches (includes reprints) - 1956-1970 (Box 36)
    - Articles and speeches, Miscellaneous (Box 37)
    - Book Reviews, Miscellaneous (Box 37)
    - Book Reviews and Letters to Editors, Miscellaneous (Box 37)
    - Notes - Address and Invitation Lists (Box 38)
    - Notes - Miscellaneous (Box 38)
    - Note Cards (Box 38)
    - Note Cards (Box 39)
    - Diary/Datebooks, 1932-1979 (Box 40–43)
  - Manuscripts by others: (Box 44)
    - Brownlow, Louis:
      - Autobiography (partial) (Box 44)
      - Diary (partial) (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 45)
  - Documents (Box 45)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Political Science 1, 25 (Box 46)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Political Science 25 30 (Box 47)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Political Science 30 (Box 48)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Political Science 30.5 (Box 49)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Political Science 31.5 (Box 49)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Political Science 31.5 (Box 50–51)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Political Science 32, 70.5, U752 (Box 52)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Urbanism/Urban Studies (Box 52)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Urbanism/Urban Studies (Box 53)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Urbanism/Urban Studies (Box 54)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Conservation 77 (Box 54)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Miscellaneous (Box 54)
  - Course Materials - Brooklyn College - Miscellaneous (Box 55)
  - Course Materials - Chicago, University of (Box 56)
  - Course Materials - City University of New York - Urbanism (Box 56)
  - Course Materials - Columbia University Seminars (Box 56)
  - Course Materials - Nova University (Tallahassee) (Box 56)
  - Course Materials - Nova University (Box 57)
  - Course Materials - Pratt Institute (Box 57)
  - Course Materials - Reading Lists, miscellaneous (Box 57)
  - Organizations: (Box 57)
  - A (miscellaneous) (Box 58)
  - Afro-Asian Organization for Economic Cooperation (AFRASEC) (Box 58)
  - American Committee for International Municipal Cooperation (Box 58)
  - American Consortium for International Public Administration (Box 58)
  - American Friends Service Committee (Box 59)
  - American Institute of Architects (Box 59)
  - American Institute of Planners (AIP) - General (Box 59)
  - American Institute of Planners (AIP) - AIP/ASPO International Committee (Box 59)
  - American Institute of Planners - New York Chapter (Box 60)
  - American Institute of Planners (AIP) - Scope and Purpose (Box 60)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) (Box 60)
  - American Public Health Association (APHA) - General (Box 60)
  - American Public Health Association (APHA) - Code Enforcement (Box 60)
  - American Public Health Association - Housing Legislation (Box 61)
  - American Public Health Association - Rural Housing (Box 61)
  - American Public Works Association (Box 61)
  - American Society of Public Administration (ASPA) - General, 1952-1965 (Box 61)
  - American Society of Public Administration (ASPA) - General, 1970-1979 mixed years (Box 62)
  - American Society of Public Administration (ASPA) - Academy (Box 62)
  - ASPA:
    - Comparative Administration (Box 63)
    - Conferences, 1946-1974 (Box 63)
    - Council (Box 63)
    - Elections (Box 63)
    - Finance (Box 63)
  - ASPA:
    - History (Box 64)
    - International (Box 64)
    - International Day, 1959 (Box 64)
    - Moscow Meeting (Box 64)
    - New York Chapter (Box 64)
  - ASPA: (Box 65)
    - President (Box 65)
    - Program Public Administration Review (Box 65)
    - Reports (Box 65)
    - Research - Committees - History (Box 65)
    - Section on International and Comparative Administration (SICA) American (Box 65)
  - Society of Planning Officials (ASPO) - General, 1966-1974 (Box 65)
  - ASPO: (Box 66)
    - General, 1975-1979 mixed years (Box 66)
    - Reports (Box 66)
    - Ways & Means Committee (Box 66)
  - Asia Foundation (Box 66)
  - Association of Collegiate Schools of Planning (Box 66)
  - Building Research Advisory Board (BRAB) (Box 67)
  - Centre Africain de Formation.. .(CAFRAD) (Box 67)
  - Citizens' Housing and Planning Council of New York (CHPC) – General, 1949-1964 (Box 67)
  - CHPC - General - mixed years (Box 68)
  - CHPC - Board (Box 68)
  - CHPC:
    - Committee on the City Planning Commission (Box 69)
    - Emergency Committee on Low Rent Housing (Box 69)
    - Enforcement (Box 69)
    - Executive Committee (Box 69)
    - News and Reviews (Box 69)
    - President (Box 69)
    - Progress (Box 69)
    - Recreation (Box 69)
    - Relocation Committee (Box 69)
    - Special Reports (Box 69)
  - Citizens Union - General (Box 70)
  - Citizens Union - CHPC - Community Boards (Box 70)
  - Citizens Union - City Managers Committee (Box 70)
  - City Club (Box 70)
  - City Housing Corporation (Box 70)
  - College-Federal Agency Council (Box 71)
  - College of Europe (Bruges) (Box 71)
  - Committee for Nonprofessional Collegiate Schools of Planning (Box 71)
  - Community Planning Board 7,NewYork City (CBP 7) -Minutes and General Files, 1951-1969 (Box 71)
  - CPB 7:
    - Minutes and General Files, 1970-1976 (Box 72)
    - Aging (Box 72)
    - Alexanders (Box 72)
    - Borough President, Manhattan (Box 72)
    - Building Code (Box 73)
    - Capital Budget (Box 73)
    - Census Data (Box 73)
    - Chairman and Executive Committee (Box 73)
    - City Planning Commission (Box 73)
    - Committees (Box 73)
    - Community Development Program (Box 73)
    - Education (Box 73)
    - Environment (Box 73)
    - Health, Education and Welfare (Box 74)
    - Housing (Box 74)
    - Housing and Urban Development (Box 74)
    - Housing Code (Box 75)
    - Landmarks (Box 75)
    - Long-Range Planning (Box 75)
    - Master Plan (Box 75)
    - Members (Box 75)
    - Mid-West Side Planning/Action Coalition (Box 75)
    - Neighborhood Agencies (Box 75)
    - Neighborhood Government (Box 75)
    - New School Symposium (Box 75)
    - Noise Abatement (Box 75)
    - Nominating Committee (Box 75)
    - O'Connor Bill (Box 75)
    - Open House (Box 75)
    - Parks, Recreation and Culture (Box 76)
    - Publicity (Box 76)
    - Sidewalk Cafes (Box 76)
    - Single Room Occupancy Hotels (SROs) (Box 76)
    - Steering Committee (Box 76)
    - Streets and Traffic (Box 76)
  - CPB7: (Box 77)
    - Traffic and Transportation (Box 77)
    - Transportation and Environment (Box 77)
    - Waterfront (Box 77)
    - West side Highway (Box 77)
  - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion (Box 77)
  - Conseil International du Batiment(CIB) (Box 77)
  - Conseil International de 1'Organisation Scientifique Coriginally Comite International.. .3 (CIOS) (Box 77)
  - CIOS (Box 78)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 79)
  - Eastern Regional Organisation for Planning and Housing (also called East Asia Regional) (Box 79)
  - Eastern Regional Organization for Public Administration (EROPA) (Box 80)
  - Escuela Superior de Administracion Publica America Central (ESAPAC). (Box 80)
  - European Research Institute for Regional and Urban Planning (ERIRUP) (Box 80)
  - Federacion Interamericana de Institutiones de Credito... (FINICAM) (Box 80)
  - Federation Internationale de Géomètres (FIG) (Box 80)
  - Federation of West Side Block Associations, New York City (Box 81)
  - Health, Education and Welfare, U.S. Department of (HEW) (Box 81)
  - Housing and Home Finance Agency (Box 81)
  - Housing and Urban Development, U.S. Department of (HUD) (Box 81)
  - I (miscellaneous) (Box 81)
  - Indian Institute of Public Administration (Box 81)
  - Institute of Public Administration (IPA) - General (Box 81)
  - Institute of Public Administration (IPA) - Business (Box 81)
  - IPA - Program (Box 82)
  - IPA - Receptions (Box 82)
  - IPA - Reports (Box 82)
  - Interamerican Development Bank (Box 82)
  - Interamerican Planning Society. SEE: Sociedad... (SIAP) (Box 82)
  - International Academy of Comparative Law (Box 82)
  - International Assembly of Non-Governmental Organizations Concerned with the Environment (INASEN) (Box 82)
  - International Association for Housing Science (Box 82)
  - International Association of Comparative Law (Box 83)
  - International Association of Legal Science (Box 83)
  - International Association Town Planning (Box 83)
  - International Centre for Land Policy Studies (Box 83)
  - International Centre for Local Credit [also called International Information Centre.. .] (ICLC)] (Box 83)
  - ICLC (Box 84)
  - International City Managers Association (Box 84)
  - International Council of Monuments and Sites (ICOMOS) (Box 84)
  - International Federation for Housing and Planning Also called International Federation for Housing and Town Planning!] (IFHP) – General (Box 84)
  - IFHP:
    - Bureau ( -1975) (Box 85)
    - Bureau (1976-) (Box 86)
    - Congresses, 1952-1958 (Box 86)
    - Congresses, I960-I962 (Box 87)
    - Congresses, 1964-1975 (Box 87)
    - Congresses, 1976-1977 (Box 87)
    - Council, 1946-1973 (Box 87)
    - Finance (Box 87)
    - Golden Jubilee, Arnhem, 1963 (Box 90)
    - Goulbenkian Foundation (Box 90)
    - Headquarters –General and 1955-1972 (Box 90)
    - Historic Sites (Box 91)
    - International Labour Office Classification (Box 91)
    - Miller, J. Marshall (Box 91)
    - New Delhi Regional Conference (Box 91)
    - New Towns (Box 91)
    - North American Regional Section (Box 91)
    - Philadelphia AIA Film (Box 92)
    - President (Box 92)
    - Professional Planners (Box 92)
    - Program (Box 92)
    - Promotional Leaflet (Box 92)
    - Regional Planning (Box 92)
    - Rent and Income (Box 92)
    - Seminars (Box 92)
    - Sociology and Urban Planning (Box 92)
    - Traffic (Box 92)
    - United Nations (Box 92)
  - IFHP: (Box 93)
    - United Nations (Box 93)
    - U.S. Committee (Box 93)
    - Urban Renewal (Box 93)
  - International Federation of Landscape Architects (IFLA) (Box 93)
  - International Federation of Pedestrians (Box 93)
  - International Institute for Educational Planning (IIEP) (Box 93)
  - International Institute of Administrative Sciences (IIAS) (Box 94)
  - General correspondence and Miscellaneous items, 1950-1970 and n.d (Box 94)
  - IIAS:
    - Administrative Practices Committee (Box 95)
    - Administrative Procedure Committee (Box 95)
    - Colloquium - San Remo, 1960 (Box 95)
    - Comparative Administration Committee (Box 95)
    - Comparative Cases Committee (CCC)- 1959­1964 (Box 96)
    - CCC - 1962-1974 (Box 97)
    - CCC-H (Housing) - Belgium (Box 97)
    - CCC-H (Housing) - Finland (Box 97)
    - CCC-H (Housing) - France (Box 97)
    - IIAS - CCC-H: (Box 98)
      - Germany (Box 98)
      - Hungary (Box 98)
      - Ireland (Box 98)
      - Latin America (Box 98)
      - Poland (Box 98)
      - Portugal (Box 98)
      - Spain (Box 98)
      - Sweden (Box 98)
      - Turkey (Box 98)
      - United Kingdom (Box 98)
      - United States (Box 98)
      - Yugoslavia (Box 98)
    - Congresses, 1953-1968 (Box 99)
    - Congresses, 1971-1977 (Box 100)
    - Contracts Committee (Box 100)
    - Council (Box 101)
    - Ethical Standards (Box 101)
    - Executive Committee (Box 101)
    - Finance Committee (Box 102)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 102)
    - Headquarters (Box 102)
    - Housing Procedure (Box 102)
    - Informatique (Box 102)
    - International Sections (Box 102)
    - Meetings and Round tables, Miscellaneous (Box 103)
    - Non-Governmental Organizations (Box 103)
    - Periodicals (Box 103)
    - Planning and Forecasting Committee (Box 103)
    - President (Box 103)
    - Progress in Public Administration (journal) (Box 103)
    - Promotional Brochure (Box 104)
    - Publications Committee (Box 104)
    - Reorganization, 1973 (Box 104)
    - Report by Charles S. Ascher: "Public Provision of Housing.. ." 1970-1971 (Box 104)
    - Review of Activities (Box 104)
    - Roundtables, 1954-1976 (Box 105)
    - Schools and Institutes (Box 106)
    - Scientific Committee (Box 106)
    - Stassen, Jacques - Study (Box 106)
    - Statutes (Box 107)
    - Survey: American Report (Box 107)
    - Training Institutes (Box 107)
    - United Nations (Box 107)
    - United Nations (Box 108)
    - UNESCO (Box 108)
    - U.S. Consortium (Box 108)
    - U.S. Contribution (Box 109)
    - Civil U.S. Section, 1947-1968 (Box 109)
  - IIAS: (Box 110)
    - U.S. Section, 1969-1970 (Box 110)
    - Water Pollution (Box 110)
    - World Health Organization International Legal Center International Organization of Supreme Audit Institutions (INTOSAI) (Box 110)
  - International Political Science Association (IPSA) (Box 111)
  - International Public Personnel Association (Box 111)
  - International Society of City and Regional Planners (Box 111)
  - International Studies Association (ISA) (Box 111)
  - International Union of Architects (Box 111)
  - International Union of Local Authorities (IULA) - General, 1949-1954 and n.d. (Box 111)
  - IULA:
    - General, 1955-1977 (Box 112)
    - Africa/Asia (Box 112)
    - Citizen Participation (Box 112)
    - Computers (Box 112)
    - Congresses, 1947, 1959 196l (Box 112)
    - Congresses, 1963-1977 (Box 113)
    - Council (Box 113)
    - Environment (Box 114)
    - Executive Committee, 1956-1967 (Box 114)
    - Executive Committee, 1971-1977 (Box 115)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 115)
    - Headquarters (Box 115)
    - Municipal Social Work (Box 115)
    - National Association (Box 116)
    - Stockholm Conference, 1967 (Box 116)
    - Technical Assistance (Box 116)
    - Town Twinning (Box 116)
    - Training Courses (Box 116)
    - U.K. Section (Box 117)
    - U.N. - ECOSOC (Box 117)
    - U.N. - Human Rights (Box 117)
    - U.N. - Municipal Finance (Box 117)
    - U.N. - S.O.A (Bureau of Social Affairs) (Box 117)
    - UNESCO (Box 117)
  - IULA: (Box 118)
    - UNICEF (Box 118)
    - World Health Organizations (Box 118)
  - Interparliamentary Union (Box 118)
  - Interuniversity Case Program (Box 118)
  - Metropolitan Committee on Planning (METCOP) (Box 118)
  - Rational Academy of Public Administration (NAPA) - General (Box 119)
  - Rational Academy of Public Administration (NAPA) - Business (Box 119)
  - NAPA: (Box 120)
    - Environment (Box 120)
    - International (Box 120)
    - Members (Box 120)
  - NAPA: (Box 121)
    - Newsletter (Box 121)
    - Le Substantive (Box 121)
    - Watergate (Box 121)
  - National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials (originally National Association of Housing Officials] (NAHRO):
    - General (Box 121)
    - Ascher, Charles S. - Speech to NAHO, 1935 (Box 121)
    - Hale - Housing Stock Study (Box 121)
    - International Committee Documents;, 1960, 1943 (Box 121)